{
    "id": "514109de71e7486db35d0b724f81c7a3",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I would be surprised if he ........................",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "wins",
                "won",
                "had won"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5c4a79f8791b4bf199319253a623284e"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had known, I ......................... you straightaway.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will tell",
                "would tell",
                "would have told"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d5b37aaaf79245cbb314a9eeea826446"
        },
        {
            "question": "Rarely ................................ such a good film.",
            "description": "When the sentence begins with expressions like rarely, hardly or only, the auxiliary verb goes before the subject. ",
            "answers": [
                "I have seen",
                "Have I seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ff568aa255cc45e9b0f793ba1c6db94e"
        },
        {
            "question": "My father often ........................ a nap in the afternoon.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about facts, routines and habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "take",
                "is taking",
                "takes"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a9201879a9ea406492e1aca51fd878a1"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you don't want to go, you ...........................",
            "description": "We use 'need not' to show the lack of obligation. ",
            "answers": [
                "mustn't",
                "needn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c9b029aa26634153a7b7d9f8db73e87d"
        },
        {
            "question": "You don't need ........................... on Saturdays.",
            "description": "When need is used as an ordinary verb, it is followed by an infinitive with to. ",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "to work"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c134b98c5f594217a598ae9fd6854ec9"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ..................................... on Saturdays.",
            "description": "When need is used as a modal auxiliary, it is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "need not work",
                "need not to work"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0b30ab624f45413d86569c9f74c514c1"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ............................. you, I would accept this offer.",
            "description": "Both 'was' and 'were' are possible here however, 'were' is preferred. ",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "were",
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "dc220c84d9d14482be0c3cca24055fbf"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ............................... mend your ways.",
            "description": "We use 'had better' to give strong advice. ",
            "answers": [
                "have better",
                "had better",
                "should better"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b1577f00339c4b6692657bd32ae475bd"
        },
        {
            "question": "She .............................. that she would come.",
            "description": "After 'tell' we use a personal object. ",
            "answers": [
                "told",
                "told me",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "60f9cad030c448ba92cfac86b5fd79f6"
        },
        {
            "question": "I sent ....................... a letter yesterday.",
            "description": "'Sent' is one of those verbs that can be followed by two objects - a direct object and an indirect object. When the indirect object goes first, there is no preposition. ",
            "answers": [
                "him",
                "to him",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "207bb44931064a7c9aaf81258148aab6"
        },
        {
            "question": "I sent flowers ..........................",
            "description": "'Sent' is one of those verbs that can be followed by two objects - a direct object and an indirect object. When the direct object goes first, we use the preposition 'to' or 'for' before the indirect object. ",
            "answers": [
                "her",
                "to her",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5ad716461f264a8294e144e004d15a88"
        }
    ]
}